Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
1505-1957 (inclusive),
1702-1854 (bulk).
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Hyde 10
19 boxes and 1 vol. (9.5 linear ft.)
A collection of single letters, documents, and manuscripts, primarily dating to the 18th century, from the collection of Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles.
*2003JM-35 (part), *2003JM-47 (part), *2003JM-57 (part), *2003JM-58, *2003JM-64 (part), *2003JM-207 (part), and *2003JM-236 (part). All items are *2003JM-58 unless otherwise noted. Bequest of Mary Hyde Eccles, Four Oaks Farm, Somerville, New Jersey; received: 2004.
Provenance
The Hyde Autograph Collection is a part of the Donald and Mary Hyde Collection of Dr. Samuel Johnson, which was collected by Donald Frizell Hyde (1909-1966) and Mary Hyde, later Viscountess Eccles (1912-2003). Approximately half of the Autograph Collection was acquired in 1950, as part of an extra-illustrated copy of Boswell's Life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. from the collection of A.B. Burney (Sotheby's, 1950 Apr. 24, lot 153). The volume was disbound in 1953. At least 84 other items had been removed by the Hydes at various times from three extra-illustrated sets they had acquired from R.B. (Robert Borthwick) Adam in 1948 (now MS Hyde 75, 76, and 77). The remainder of the Hyde Autograph File was acquired by the Hydes singly or in small groups from various sources from 1941 to 2002.
Arranged alphabetically by author.
This collection includes many of the unbound single items in the Donald and Mary Hyde Collection of Dr. Samuel Johnson. To see finding aids for the other Hyde manuscripts, enter "MS Hyde" in the OASIS search box, using quotation marks.
Many of the items in the Hyde Autograph Collection relate in some way to Samuel Johnson and his extended circle. The collection includes significant letters from Joseph Addison, Sir Joseph Banks, Jeremy Bentham, William Cowper, Daniel Defoe, Jonathan Edwards, Thomas Hobbes, T.E. Lawrence, John Locke, John Stuart Mill, Alexander Pope, Sir Walter Scott, Percy Bysshe Shelley, and Horace Walpole. Another highlight is a letter of introduction written by Gilbert Walmsley for Samuel Johnson and David Garrick on their first journey to London. Many of the items concern bookselling and publishing in late eighteenth-century England.
The R.B. Adam Library Relating to Dr. Samuel Johnson and his Era, Volume the Third (London: Oxford University Press, 1929).
- Abington, Mrs., (Frances Barton), 1737-1815. Autograph letter, [London?] to James Lacy, [between 1765-1774?], (1); 1s.
  Invites Lacy to rehearse at her home for the part of Oakly in George Colman's The Jealous Wife. Probably written after Abington's return to Lacy's Drury Lane Theatre in 1765.
- Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Sir Richard Steele, 1712 Apr. 19., (2); 1s.
  Testifies for the character of the unidentified bearer's husband.
- Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Place [London] to unidentified recipient, 1710 Feb. 18., (3); 1s.
  Asks for assistance in securing patent in Ireland.
- Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719. Document, signed, Signet Office [London] 1718 Feb. 14., (4); 1s.
  Fragment of a document signed by Addison "by his Majesty's command." Also signed by William Cooke.
- Aikin, John, 1747-1822. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1800 Jan. 31., (5); 1s.
  Critiques a new medical text, possibly William Nisbet's The Clinical Pharmacopoeia. May be addressed to the publishers of that work, J. Johnson and J. Watson.
- Aikin, Lucy, 1781-1864. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead (London), to unidentified recipient, [1825?] Sept. 6., (6); 1s.
  Discusses arrangements for a memorial to Mrs. (Anna Letitia) Barbauld, who died in 1825. Includes a draft of an epitaph, in an unknown hand.
- Akam, John. Bond: document, signed, [no place] 1749 Dec. 30., (7); 1s.
  Bond for a loan from Mary Dalley, witnessed by John Golding and John Albright. On verso, receipt, signed, from Golding to David Garrick, 1760 Nov. 15, witnessed by George Garrick.
- Akam, John. Bond: autograph document, signed, Hampton upon Thames (London), to Elizabeth Mason, 1750 Aug. 8., (8); 1s.
  Bond for a loan, witnessed by E. Clutterbuck and Joseph Lockley. On verso, two receipts, signed, from Elizabeth Mason to Mr. Garrick, 1753 Oct. 23 and 1760 June 26. The receipts were apparently written out by David Garrick for her signature.
- Albemarle, George Thomas Keppel, Earl of, 1799-1891. Autograph letter, signed, 29a Grosvenor Square [London] to unidentified recipient, [18--] June 8., (9); 1s.
  Thanks for loan of Penny Magazine.
- Alexander, Benjamin, d. 1768. Agreement: document, signed, [no place] 1765 May 18., (10); 1s.
  Publishing agreement for The Seats and Causes of Diseases Investigated by Anatomy, a translation of Giambattista Morgani's work. Signed by publishers Andrew Millar and Joseph Johnson (1738-1809), and witness James Seare. On verso, a receipt from executors Richard Cooke and William Cooke to Thomas Cadell.
- Amherst, Jeffery Amherst, Baron, 1717-1797. Autograph letter, signed, Whitehall (London), to Sir George Yonge, 1786 May 31., (11); 1s.
  Concerning the replacement of two company officers.
- Anne, Queen of Great Britain, 1665-1714. Warrant: manuscript document, signed, St. James's [Palace, London] 1702 Dec. 4., (12); 1s.
  Authorizing payment to Charles Shales, royal goldsmith. Signed "anne R" at top of document, and also by Sidney Godolphin, Earl of Godolphin, Lord High Treasurer.
- "Argus." Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1789?], (13); 1s.
  Identifies Margaret Caroline Rudd as the author of The Belle Widows (London: J. Kirby, 1789). "Argus" may have been the book's publisher, James Kerby.
  *2003JM-236.
- Argyll, Jane Campbell, Duchess of, d. 1767. Agreement: document, signed, [no place] 1765 June 12., (14); 1s.
  Agreement to sell the Adderbury estate to her daughter Caroline Townshend, Countess of Greenwich (then Countess of Dalkeith) and her husband Charles Townshend (1725-1767).
- Ariosto, Lodovico, 1474-1533. Signature, [no place] 1511 Feb., (15); 1s.
  Dated signature on the title page of Giovanni Boccaccio's Genealogie. Annotated in Italian with a seal of authenticity, 1878 June 5.
- Augustus Frederick, Duke of Sussex, 1773-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Tunbridge Wells (England), to Thomas Joseph Pettigrew, 1820 Sept. 18., (16); 1s.
  Concerning his library catalog, Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
- Baker, George, Sir, 1722-1809. Autograph letter, signed, Jermyn Street [London] to Ozias Humphry, [17--] Mar. 7., (17); 1s.
  Seeks support for nephew Dr. Rhodes in his candidacy for physician to St. George's Hospital.
- Ballantyne, James, 1772-1833. Autograph letter, signed, Printing Office, Edinburgh (Scotland), to W. Berry, 1807 May 20., (18); 1s.
  Asks for help in securing publisher for new edition of the works of Junius. On verso, autograph letter, signed, from Berry to Vernor, Hood Sharpe, [1807 May 22] forwarding Ballantyne's letter, and reporting on the progress of the next volume of The Beauties of England and Wales.
- Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820. Autograph letter, signed, Revesby Abbey [Lincolnshire, England] to William Aiton, 1785 Aug. 29., (19); 1s.
  Seeking a botanist to accompany an expedition to the coast of Africa under Edward Thompson.
- Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820. Autograph letter, signed, Soho Square [London] to William Henry Cavendish-Bentinck, Duke of Portland, 1802 Dec. 22., (20); 1s.
  Recommends Mr. Turner for the post of Sheriff of Lincolnshire.
- Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820. Autograph letter, signed, Revesby Abbey [Lincolnshire, England] to [John Holroyd, Earl of Sheffield] [1807?] Sept. 24., (21); 2s.
  Doubts whether coal can be mined at Box Hill, Surrey.
- Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820. Autograph letter, [no place] to [J.R.?] Williams, 1792 Feb. 20., (22); 1s.
  Asking for an official copy of his letter to William Wilberforce concerning the Sierra Leone Company.
- Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] to His Majesty's Exchequer, 1774 Jan. 17., (23); 1s.
  Receipt for annuity, made out to teller Thomas Townshend. Also signed by witness William Curtis.
- Barbauld, Mrs. (Anna Letitia), 1743-1825. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead [England] to E. Noble, [1789] Apr. 24., (24); 1s.
  Describes a celebration in honor of the recovery of George III, King of Great Britain.
- Barber, Frank, d. 1801. Autograph letter, signed, 47 St. John Street, Smithfield (London), to James Boswell, 1786 Jan. 7., (25); 1s.
  Forwarding Samuel Johnson letters to Boswell.
  Marshall Waingrow, ed., The Correspondence and Other Papers of James Boswell Relating to the Making of the Life of Johnson (New York: McGraw-Hill, [1969?]), 133.
- Barber, Frank, d. 1801. Autograph draft letter, signed, Lichfield (England), to James Boswell, 1787 July 9., (26); 1s.
  Discusses the relationship between Samuel Johnson and Humphrey Heeley, and criticizes the account of Sir John Hawkins. Annotated by T[homas?] Slater and in an unknown hand. Includes an autograph letter, signed, from Slater to Barber commenting upon Barber's draft.
  Aleyn Lyell Reade, Johnsonian Gleanings, Part VIII: A Miscellany (New York: Octagon Books, 1968), 75-76.
- Barnard, Thomas, 1728-1806 (then Bishop of Killaloe). Autograph letter, signed, St. Wolstan's [Ireland] to [Sir Joshua Reynolds] 1791 July 29., (27); 1s.
  Concerning admission to the Royal Academy, and the reaction of George III, King of Great Britain, to the proposed monument to Samuel Johnson. Mentions James Boswell.
- Barnard, Thomas, 1728-1806 (then Bishop of Killaloe). Autograph letter, signed, London, to Joseph C. (Joseph Cooper) Walker, 1789 May 17., (28); 2s.
  Reports on the good health of George III, King of Great Britain, and comments on the second issue of Transactions issued by the Royal Irish Academy. With cover.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 16.
- Barrington, William Wildman Barrington, Viscount, 1717-1793. Letter, signed, War Office [London] to Adair Bullock, 1778 Oct. 9., (29); 1s.
  Authorizes bounty money for infantry regiments.
- Barry, Henry, 1750-1822. Autograph letter, signed, James Street Terrace [London?] to Anna Seward, 1788 Sept. 30., (30); 1s.
  Reports on efforts to locate an army officer named Howell. Mentions Hester Lynch Piozzi. Torn at seal with some loss of text.
- Barry, James, 1741-1806. Autograph letter, signed, 36 Castle St. [London] to David Stewart Erskine, Earl of Buchan, [1802], (31); 1s.
  Hopes to have a new painting for Buchan soon.
- Bartolozzi, Gaetano Stefano, 1757-1821. Number of the etchings and proofs disposed to different friends of mine: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] [18--?], (32); 1s.
  A list of recipients of impressions of Bartolozzi's etching of Andrea del Sarto's Madonna del Sacco.
- Bath, William Pulteney, Earl of, 1684-1764. Autograph letter, [Spa, Belgium] to unidentified recipient, [1763?], (33); 1s.
  Describing a visit to Spa (Belgium). Incomplete letter, with tape repairs. The letter mentions postscripts by Elizabeth Robinson Montagu and Elizabeth Carter which are missing.
- Bayley, Nathaniel. An accurate survey round Headley Park: autograph document, signed, Headley Park [Hampshire, England] 1764 June 23., (34); 1s.
  Cover sheet only of a survey of Headley Park, the estate of Sir Thomas Gatehouse. Headley Park had been the property of William Huggins, and this document is related to the William Huggins Papers, MS Hyde 4.
- Beattie, James, 1735-1803. Autograph letter, signed, Peterhead [Scotland] to William Strahan, 1783 June 28., (35); 1s.
  Wants to know whether his Dissertations Moral and Critical has been presented to the royal family. On verso, Strahan's autograph draft letter to Beattie in response, London, 1783 July 14.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 21.
- Beaumont, George Howland, Sir, 1753-1827. Manuscript letter, Rydal Mount [Cumbria, England] to [William Wordsworth] 1826 Sept. 12., (36); 1s.
  Passes on the testimony of Sir Joshua Reynolds as to the accuracy of James Boswell's Life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. Manuscript transcript by Wordsworth's clerk John Carter.
  Robert F. Metzdorf, "A New Wordsworth Letter," Modern Language Notes, 1944 Mar., 168-170.
- Bedford, John Russell, Duke of, 1710-1771. Letter, signed, Fontainebleau (France), to [John Stuart, Earl of Bute, then Prime Minister]?, 1762 Nov. 3., (37); 1s.
  Sends the preliminaries to the 1763 peace treaty with France.
- Bell, John, 1745-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Strand [London] to unidentified recipient, 1804 Feb. 8., (38); 1s.
  Sends a prospectus.
- Bell, John. Autograph letter, signed, 17 Sloane Street [London?] to Charles Bell, 1841 Aug. 28., (39); 1s.
  Forwards a small collection of autograph letters to his brother.
- Belsham, William, 1752-1827. Receipts: autograph documents, signed, [no place] to George Robinson Co., 1794-1796., (40); 2s.
  Two receipts concerning Belsham's Memoirs of the Reign of George III and Memoirs of the Kings of Great Britain of the House of Brunswick.
- Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1862-1925. Autograph letter, signed, Magdalen College, Cambridge (England), to Ralph Straus, 1912 Aug. 15., (41); 1s.
  Declining the presidency of the Johnson Society, and commenting on the importance of Samuel Johnson to England.
  2003JM-64
- Bentham, Jeremy, 1748-1832. Autograph letter, signed, Queen Square Place [London] to David Booth, 1820 Mar. 8., (42); 1s.
  Scheduling a meeting.
  Bentham's second letter to Booth of this date. Only the first letter appeared in The Correspondence of Jeremy Bentham, Timothy L.S. Sprigge, ed.
- Bentham, Jeremy, 1748-1832. Autograph letter, signed, Moore, Paris [?] to Sir John Bowring, [1831 Jan. 15], (43); 1s.
  Concerning negotiations with a Paris bookseller.
- Bentham, Jeremy, 1748-1832. Autograph note, Queen Square Place [London] to [Henry Brougham, Baron Brougham and Vaux?] 1828 Jan. 11., (44); 1s.
- Bentinck, Charles [?] An Appeal to the Public, in a Letter to the Author of Johnsoniana: autograph manuscript, London, 1825 Mar., (45); 10 leaves
  A critique of a pamphlet entitled Johnsoniana by a Mr. Heusch, which satirized Samuel Johnson. The name Charles Bentinck is written on the title page in a different hand. The title page reads "Printed at the Philanthropic, 1825", but no copy of the Appeal, or of Heusch's original tract, have been traced. Bound, using the trimmed cover of the British Magazine for 1801 Jan.
  2003JM-64.
- Berenger, Richard, 1719 or 20-1782. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Place [London] to unidentified recipient, 1753 Oct. 2., (46); 1s.
  Offers thanks for assistance.
- Berkeley, [Eliza, 1734-1800?] Autograph letter, signed, Springarden, to [George Nugent Temple Grenville, Marquess of Buckingham] 1788 Oct. 21., (47); 1s.
  Offers best wishes to Lady Buckingham.
- Besant, Walter, Sir, 1836-1901. Notes on Samuel Johnson: autograph manuscript, [no place] [18--], (48); 1s.
  Page of an unidentified Besant manuscript, describing Samuel Johnson's dedication of the Dictionary to Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of Chesterfield.
- Bindley, James, 1737-1818. Autograph note, Stamp Office [London] to John Boydell, [between 1782-1804] Monday morning., (49); 1s.
  Requesting a portfolio for storing prints. Written after Boydell's election as an alderman in 1782.
- Bindley, James, 1737-1818. Autograph letter, Stamp Office [London] to William Monck Mason, 1815 Dec. 14., (50); 1s.
  Cannot identify the pamphlet mentioned by Samuel Johnson in his Jonathan Swift entry in Lives of the English Poets; expresses frustration over the poor quality of Johnson's citations in general.
- Birch, Thomas, 1705-1766. Autograph note, [no place] to Emanuel Mendes da Costa, 1765 Aug. 5., (51); 1s.
  Recommends Dr. Demoeux, a professor of botany at Université de Caen, for admission to the Royal Society library.
- Blacklock, Thomas, 1721-1791. 7 manuscript letters to Robert Dodsley, 1754-1756., (52); 8s.
  Letters from the poet to his publisher, written by a series of unidentified amanuenses. The letters discuss the author's blindness, his poems, and his dealings with Joseph Spence;; David Hume; and George Lyttelton, Baron Lyttelton.
- Blackwell, Thomas, 1701-1757. Agreement: document, signed, Chapter Coffee House [London] 1753 Aug. 8., (53); 1s.
  Agreement to purchase copyright to Blackwell's Memoirs of the Court of Augustus. Signed by booksellers Charles Hetch,; Thomas Longman,; Andrew Millar,; Robert Dodsley, and John Rivington.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Blagden, Charles, Sir, 1748-1820. Autograph letter, signed, Birmingham (England), to Sir Joseph Banks, 1785 Aug. 6., (54); 1s.
  Report on the progress of topological surveys. Mentions Joseph Priestley.
- Blair, Hugh, 1718-1800. Register: manuscript transcript, [London] 1796 Dec. 8., (55); 1s.
  Manuscript copy of page from the register book of the Stationers' Company, recording the receipt of Blair's sermon The Compassion and Beneficence of the Deity. Transcript by Robert Horsfield, clerk.
- Boddington, Samuel, d. 1843. 2 autograph letters, signed, to [Richard Sharp] 1816., (56); 2s.
  Letter dated 1816 May 13 expresses gratitude for his time at Fredley Farm [Mickleham, Surrey, England] A letter dated only Upper Brook Street [London?] "Monday afternoon," probably written on the same date, mentions plans to deliver portraits of Edmund Burke and Sir Joshua Reynolds, bought for Sharp at Hester Lynch Piozzi's Streatham Park auction on 1816 May 12 and 13.
  The Streatham Park auction is discussed in Edward A. Bloom and Lillian D. Bloom, The Piozzi Letters (Newark, Del.: University of Delaware Press, 1999) 5, 482-490.
- Bolton, Charles Powlett, Duke of, ca. 1718-1765. Autograph letter, signed, Portsmouth (England), to unidentified recipient, [1760] Aug. 28., (57); 1s.
  Reporting on the inadequate size of the Hampshire regiment.
- Boothby, Brooke, Sir, 1743-1824. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Ozias] Humphry, [not before 1777], (58); 1s.
  Wants to commission a portrait. Written after Humphry's return from Italy in 1777.
- Boothby, Brooke, Sir, 1743-1824. Autograph letter, [no place] to [Sir Richard St. George Mansergh St. George] [1789 Oct.?], (59); 1s.
  Discusses his daughter Penelope Boothby (1785-1791), and his duties as a justice of the peace. Remarks favorably on events preceding the French Revolution, including the forced return of Louis XVI, King of France, to Paris. Includes a draft of an epitaph of his father Sir Brooke Boothby (1710-1789).
- Boscawen, Frances Evelyn, 1719-1805. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to William Seward, [ca. 1778 June?] Wednesday midnight., (60); 1s.
  Asks Seward to solicit the assistance of Hester Lynch Piozzi (then Mrs. Thrale) with a charitable case; wishes Mrs. Thrale a son; comments on Parliament's decision to pay the debts of the late William Pitt, Earl of Chatham. Addressed to Seward at the Thrales' Streatham Park home.
- Bosville, Diana, 1722-1795. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Susannah?] Wilson, of Broomhead [Yorkshire, England] [between 1773-1782]., (61); 1s.
  Mentions Daniel Solander, a curator at the British Museum (served 1773-1782).
- Boucher, Jonathan, 1738-1804. Autograph letter, signed, Epsom (England), to Frederick Nolan, 1804 Feb. 1., (62); 1s.
  Offers to pass on his unpublished notes toward a lexicographical history of the English language, which he has been unable to complete.
- Boydell, Josiah, 1752-1817. Autograph letter, signed, West End [Hampstead, London] to John Browne (1742-1801), 1791 Feb. 27., (63); 1s.
  Rejects Browne's sketch of a proposed illustration for William Shakespeare's Richard II.
- Breval, John, 1680?-1738. Agreement: document, signed, [no place] 1724 Apr. 18., (64); 1s.
  Agreement with bookseller Bernard Lintot for the publication of Breval's Remarks on Several Parts of Europe. In Lintot's hand, with Breval's signature, and also signed by witnesses John Crawley and S. (Samuel) Jebb. With autograph memorandum, signed, by Lintot, 1725 Jan. 15.
- Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868. Autograph letter, signed, Belleville [Balavil, Inverness-shire, Scotland] to Henry Harrison, of Phones, Scotland, 1834 Aug. 11., (65); 1s.
  Concerning hunting privileges at Newtonmore, Banffshire, Scotland.
- Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868. Autograph letter, signed, Allerly, Melrose (Scotland) to Sir Nicholas Harris Nicolas, 1832 Mar. 25., (66); 1s.
  Will send a copy of the new Edinburgh Journal of Science with Nicolas's article; discusses the ills of modern publishing; praises Nicolas's Life of Burns.
- Bright, Henry, b. 1723 or 4. Autograph letter, signed, Abingdon School [Berkshire, England] to Samuel Johnson, 1770 Mar. 31., (67); 1s.
  Concerning the progress of student Ralph Plumbe, nephew of Henry Thrale. Plumbe has attempted to read Johnson's Prince of Abissinia. Written in response to a letter from Johnson dated 1770 Mar. 1 which is not recorded in Bruce Redford's The Letters of Samuel Johnson.
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. Autograph letter, signed, Rochdale (England) to unidentified recipient, 1863 July 29., (68); 1s.
  Concerning a "New York machine" designed by a Mr. Wilkinson for use in America.
- Bristol, Elizabeth Chudleigh, Countess of, 1720-1788 (then Duchess of Kingston upon Hull). Letter, signed, Paris, to George Payne, 1788 Feb. 29., (69); 1s.
  Concerning a legal case.
- Bruce, James, 1730-1794. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to [Charles Joseph?] Panckoucke, 1790 Jan. 3., (70); 1s.
  In French. Mentions banker Sir Robert Herries.
- Bruce, James, 1730-1794. Autograph letter, signed, Kinnaird [Scotland] to Maria Woodley Riddell, 1792 Sept. 16., (71); 1s.
  Describes his health problems.
- Brunet, Jacques-Charles, 1780-1867. Autograph letter, signed, Paris, to unidentified recipient, 1861 Mar. 15., (72); 1s.
  Concerning American books. In French.
- Brunet, Jacques-Charles, 1780-1867. Account: autograph document, signed, [no place] to, 1822 Aug. 28., (73); 1s.
  Account concerning his Manuel du libraire et de l'amateur de livres, with M. Ponthieu. In French.
- Bryant, Jacob, 1715-1804. Autograph letter, signed, Cypenham [Buckinghamshire, England] to unidentified recipient, 1801 Dec. 10., (74); 1s.
  Offers congratulations.
- Brydges, Egerton, Sir, 1762-1837. Autograph letter, signed, Lee [Kent, England] to J.S. Brooks, Esq., 1828 Jan. 4., (75); 1s.
  Concerning the financial claims of Mr. Aldersey against Brydges.
- Buchan, David Stewart Erskine, Earl of, 1742-1829. Autograph letter, signed, Dryburgh Abbey [Berwickshire, Scotland] to John Henning, 1802 May 9., (76); 1s.
  Discusses Henning's plan for a sculpture.
- Buchan, David Stewart Erskine, Earl of, 1742-1829. Autograph letter, signed, Kirkhill (Scotland: Parish), to unidentified recipient, 1788 May 18., (77); 1s.
  Concerning the lack of respect granted to the Scotch peerage.
- Buckingham, George Nugent Temple Grenville, Marquess of, 1753-1813. Autograph letter, signed, Stowe (Buckinghamshire, England), to unidentified recipient, 1780 Dec. 3., (78); 1s.
  Concerning orders for his regiment.
- Burgh, [William, 1741-1808]? Notes on Samuel Johnson: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--?], (79); 1s.
  Fragment of a critique of Samuel Johnson's piety and scholarship, attributed to "Dr. Burgh."
- Burney, Charles, 1757-1817. Autograph letter, Greenwich (London, England), to Charles Parr Burney, 1810 June 2., (80); 1s.
  Regarding efforts to secure patronage from George III, King of Great Britain.
- Burney, Charles, 1757-1817. Autograph letter, signed, Greenwich (London, England), to P. (Patrick) Kelly, 1812 May 16., (81); 1s.
  Concerning payment of Cox's subscription.